It's not a right angle, but if you can sew it up, it's a V-shape.
If you use a V-shape and a flat line together, it will jump up.
For the pants, we also use a linear pattern.
After the linear pattern is poured in, we arrange the pattern.
There's a lot of content I want to talk about, so I have to be a little more serious.
If I talk too fast, I tend to forget what I want to talk about.
Because there's too much to do.
After wearing the pants, I try not to mix the pattern with the body as much as possible.
Because I adjusted the number of patterns of this model relatively widely.
So,
So when you are arranging, you can't just put the pants on.
You have to rearrange it.
Okay.
After that, we will activate the rise.
Before that, we put the top one.
Those few panels.
Because we just chose these few panels.
The other panels are all frozen.
Why are the other panels frozen?
Because after you change these panels, they must be particularly tight.
You can see.
When you are particularly tight, there is no wrinkle at all.
If you go to activate the front and middle panels now,
Let them simulate together.
This part of the buckle.
It will be pulled to deform.
Once the buckle is pulled to deform, it starts to shake.
Or the shape is wrong.
It's very tiring for you to fix it again.
So we're going to freeze these unrelated panels first.
Okay.
Now our pants are completely on the inside of the panel.
At this time, we can return its tail compression rate.
Okay.
So we quickly put the pants on the outside of the clothes.
Then you can activate the panel to simulate again.
You see.
Even if I just changed it a little bit like this.
Because the overall clothes are still in a very tight state.
Then you have a space.
There are some instability and shaking.
In such a situation.
First of all, we can see.
By resetting the 3D position.
To reset the position of the button.
If this method.
If it doesn't work.
Then we can use other methods.
First of all, let's use the button.
Let the button and the buckle not be connected together.
Just unhook the button first.
After unhooking, let's simulate.
Okay.
After the simulation.
Let's do it manually.
For example, drag the panel.
Then add the pin.
Press the W key.
Then press the plus pin.
After adding the pin.
Cover the two panels.
After covering.
Then buckle the button and the buckle.
After they are stable.
Then delete the excess pin.
Because the button and the buckle are buckled together.
They are two points.
Directly to work.
So you have to understand it yourself.
You have to close the door first.
Then buckle the button.
So it won't be unstable.
Okay.
Next is to change the pants.
First of all, let's make the side of the pants wider.
How wide is it?
Just click on this hard drawing.
Look.
The pants are also wide and loose.
But it's still flat here.
There is no fold.
Its crotch.
Because we just mentioned it.
You are.
All the folds are affected by force.
And produced.
For example.
Your crotch gives it a force.
And then.
There is a force on the bottom.
Or your knees have a force on the top.
Or your hips.
There is a force coming out of the outside.
To produce a fold here.
So.
Whether it's clothes or pants.
You will see my side.
Will add some points to it.
Including our pants.
You are also waiting.
We are going to adjust it in sections.
Today.
Today's.
Lesson.
In fact.
I hope that after everyone has learned.
Can form a systematic concept.
That is, how do you change your clothes and pants in the future?
How to change.
How to learn to change.
Is.
There is a systematic way to change.
Instead of.
Hey.
I'll just change it here.
Ah.
I'm there.
There's less.
Then change.
Then change to the end.
You will find.
Ah.
It's better not to change at the beginning.
It's better to look good.
Right?
Yes.
You have to change systematically.
You can't change it casually.
Because sometimes.
Ah.
Don't talk about you.
It's me.
If I change it very casually.
Just.
I don't care about him.
I just.
Um.
There's more here.
I'll change it a little bit.
There's less there.
If I change it a little bit.
In the end.
I will find.
Ah.
Just.
I'll go back to this.
The state of opening at the beginning.
Right?
I said.
This.
Situation.
You must have met everyone.
Just changed it for half a day.
Found.
Ah.
It's better to look better at the beginning.
And then there's a physical attribute.
I changed it for half a day.
Found.
Ah.
It's still a default physical attribute.
It looks the most comfortable.
It's always like this.
Then we go through the internal line.
Cut out the waist part of the shoulder strap.
Then adjust the position of this waist.
Ah.
Make this waist part reasonable.
Width.
Okay.
Then we're going to change it.
His.
The pants part.
Okay.
First.
Let's take a look.
After opening the transparency,
Check how many parts of the human body will protrude.
First,
The position of the widest part of the pelvis.
It will have a spot outbite.
This point is usually the widest.
The most out of place.
You see.
The design of the pants is always like this.
First spit it out,
then it will keep going in.
In, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in, in.
At this time, you add a dot to the widest part of the hip.
Usually, when I model, you can see that the thighs of the pants are very tight and very close to each other.
And then it's the knees that are loose.
So we pay attention to the effect of the stitch.
We usually say that the crotch will always be in a tight state.
In this way, we can continue to pile up the fabric underneath and let it stay in your crotch.
Can you understand?
Your crotch has wrinkles here.
You have to manually pile up the fabric on the crotch and it won't fall off.
Just like our upper body waist here.
You pile it up and then you close your waist here.
It will be here.
It's like a rubber band.
It won't fall down.
This crotch can continue to stay in this position.
It sounds like it's hard.
But we'll wait.
Is there a way to put the finished picture into the picture?
The finished picture.
Because the finished picture is the last time I changed the action.
So you will see that his crotch has actually been erased by me.
Because the whole.
The whole fabric behind me has changed to a bigger fabric.
Plus this action.
In fact, after I changed this action, I found that this crotch is not very obvious.
But in the middle, you will see that he has a crotch.
You can see it.
Back to the video.
Where did I just talk about?
And then add two points here on the knee.
Because the knee is also a control in the middle.
His control is the same as we add a straight line in the elbow or in the waist.
You have to control his mid-point movement.
Instead of the whole side is a line.
Many times we.
I saw a look at your pants.
This side is a complete line.
I was thinking.
Don't you think it's very troublesome to change when you change?
Right?
We have to plan to divide this pants into two areas.
Can you finish this set at 10 o'clock?
Well.
Maybe.
Because this is a video.
It's just that I'm talking fast and slow.
Here we put the pants here.
Give him a fabric first.
Cotton Garb.
This fabric.
This fabric is the fabric of our cardigan pants.
It is a kind of fabric material that we use more often.
Physical properties.
Now you drag this crotch.
When you pull the fabric up.
You will see that there are already some wrinkles on the crotch.
Right?
Let's reduce the example first.
Then reduce the thickness of the conflict.
These are all regular operations.
In fact, there are already some wrinkles at this time.
Then you have to remember.
No matter how we change this pants.
The width of the crotch here.
We are basically set.
I won't change it again.
In addition.
I will wear it again.
Because.
In the software.
The default model's posture in the software.
It is that the feet are parallel.
We have a lot of pants in real life.
That is.
You are.
Continuously.
For example.
People are walking.
Or do some posture.
There will be wrinkles on the crotch here.
So let's choose first.
Press Shift X.
You can open the crotch.
After opening the crotch.
Choose a joint point.
The upper right corner here is the symmetrical corner.
Then.
Put this leg.
Give him a little.
Stand a little.
Is the leg standing a little bit apart.
But if you use your own model.
There will be no such problem.
Because in general.
You won't be this.
Just.
The posture of standing straight.
Generally speaking.
It is more common.
There are some curves on the arm.
Then.
There are some curves on the knee.
This is all OK.
At this time.
Are we down?
There are already some wrinkles.
Right.
Then.
Just open this transparency.
You will see that the crotch is too close to the model.
So.
Let's pull the crotch down a little bit.
After that.
Look at the crotch.
There are still wrinkles here.
Under the situation.
Then.
Let's change the other parts little by little.
I put the crotch down this time.
Purely because I think.
This pants.
It's too close to life.
I don't like it.
So I'll change it.
Sometimes.
For example.
You want to do that kind of.
The pants are not particularly long.
Is the version.
For example.
The kind of haren pants.
It's the kind of crotch pants.
Then you might change the pants.
A little longer.
Okay.
After that.
Here.
I just.
There is a point on the knee.
Then.
Did we add a break point on the top before?
There is a break point in the knee.
This break point.
In fact.
It can maintain.
The line above this point.
Not affected.
Then.
At this time.
Because there is a break point here.
Ah.
The point below us.
To move it.
It won't affect.
The bottom of it.
This is.
Its upper part of the curve.
Then.
Including.
If you want me to change.
When the knee.
This thigh.
Towards the top.
The position above the thigh.
Not affected.
Then.
You add a point in this position.
Just like me.
Here.
Add a point.
Is the level.
With this level.
The position.
Here.
Add a point here.
Okay.
At this time.
We have to go.
Even if we want to.
Change the width.
Because now.
This.
The pants.
It's not particularly loose.
Then.
We'll put it.
The knee.
A little wider.
Okay.
Here.
You can see.
In fact.
As we stretch our knees.
It has already.
Some wrinkles.
Right.
When we go to.
The hip.
Here.
You just.
A little bit.
Change these points.
You see.
When we move.
This.
Cross.
The area above the hip.
Just.
This area.
We actually.
Is not affected.
Understand?
This is.
We play.
So many points.
Use.
For.
This.
The position of the hip.
Just.
The hip.
And.
Will not.
Be affected.
So.
We can.
If we ask.
How about here.
What happened?
Why.
Why is it 20???
Because.
This is a video.
I am not.
The same.
Operation.
Wait a second.
Let me.
Pour some water.
Okay.
About.
Where.
Then.
We'll.
Change.
The knee.
Point.
The front.
Cut.
Good.
Or.
Can.
In.
On the back.
or at least make sure that they are not too far apart from each other.
Oh, are you talking about the corner of the foot?
It doesn't matter if it's the corner of the foot.
If it's the side, make sure they are not too far apart.
Don't bend the front like this,
and then bend the back like this.
Just don't.
Okay?
Where are we?
Okay, let's take a look at it again.
For example, I'm going to make some creases here.
I'm going to draw an inner line in the middle,
and then cut and sew it.
After cutting and sewing,
freeze the other pieces that are in harmony with it,
and then pull this part down a little longer,
and then simulate it.
Oh, there will be creases at once.
Can you see it?
Okay, after it has creases,
let's untie the other pieces and simulate it together.
Okay, because we're going to keep freezing these sewed pieces,
and then widening them,
or we're going to keep cutting them,
so that they don't affect the other pieces.
Then we can effectively control which part we want it to have more creases.
For example,
just now I said that
you have to put this creases piled up in the cross section
for it to have creases.
So I'm going to put it...
Hey, I'm going to freeze all the pieces below the cross section first.
Make sure this piece...
This piece can't move anymore.
This piece won't move anymore.
Then simulate it together.
Oh, quickly activate the simulation.
Isn't it amazing?
So when we change the pants,
these things,
we're going to separate them into several areas.
Okay, next,
we're going to talk about creases.
Some of you must already know how to use creases.
Here we're going to talk to some of you who don't know how to use creases.
Creases are a function of the grid
of a selected part of a certain selection.
If the shrinkage rate is greater than zero,
it will expand.
If the shrinkage rate is less than zero,
it will shrink.
Okay.
Then,
if we're in a certain area,
for example, if you want to have more creases in this part of the area,
just use a ruler greater than 1
to smear it.
Press the mouse button to smear this part of the area.
This will produce more creases.
But you have to pay attention,
because it's actually just
to make a part of the grid wider.
So this function,
you'd better use a small part of it,
and don't use the whole panel.
And there's a secret to this tool.
Once you cut or merge the panels,
the grid will be rearranged.
It's not that the grid is rearranged.
It's just that this panel has some
operations that can't go back to the original shape.
It's not just about changing the length or width,
but if two panels are merged or separated,
the grid will disappear.
You have to add it again manually.
So if you want to add a grid,
you have to make sure that
these panels,
I won't give it this kind of
merging or cutting operation anymore.
Then add the grid.
Then after merging,
this curve point is not in a smooth position.
Just like that.
Look at our clothing.
It's all connected.
Connected.
If this point pops out,
just delete this point
or move it inside.
This curve looks like a very smooth position.
Okay.
Then this is something that
we can change in our pants.
Okay.
Then in addition to
this grid,
because the grid is an application
of a small part and a small part,
we can also
use the combing curve to complete
the fold effect.
We can use the combing curve to complete the fold effect.
So I'm really going to change the combing curve.
Actually,
it's just that the front and back panels are not the same length.
So the front panel will naturally have some fold.
Okay.
I'm looking at my video.
What are you doing here?
Oh, yeah.
I'm going to change the combing curve.
Finally,
the smile is because the vertical direction is above.
So when I change the smile of the smile to
So when you change it to 103, there are already a lot of random creases in the front piece.
Because the back piece does not apply shrink.
At this time, if you also apply some shrink to the back piece,
its creasing effect will have some effect.
Because we just stretched the shrink of the front piece,
the back piece will not move,
which is equivalent to lengthening the front piece in the vertical direction.
Some creases are formed by the length difference.
If you change the length of both the front and back pieces,
and they do not have a difference,
it will be the same as the original pants.
It's equivalent to the front and back have changed length.
In this way, there is no way for the creases to be distributed in this area.
So if you want to change the length, just change only one side.
Do not change both sides.
If you change both sides, you will just make the pants longer.
After the modification,
we will make the belt here.
As for the pants,
we will use the step-by-step method to solidify it.
Don't let it be affected by other things.
I have talked about how to use the step-by-step method in the previous tutorial.
If you have time after watching today's live broadcast,
you can go and watch the tutorial.
There is nothing to say about making the pants.
Here you just make a small rectangle and sew it up.
Then you can use a little harder fabric.
After sewing it up,
I found that this button will always have some impact.
Sometimes you will think that this button is shaking all the time.
If you think it is very troublesome,
you can turn off its conflict in the mouse editor.
After turning off the conflict,
the button and the panel will no longer have conflicts.
It will not be unstable.
It will remain in the current form,
just like a copy.
Then we sew up the belt version.
As for the door and pocket of the pants,
I have talked about it in the last video.
If you don't know much about making pants,
such as door and pocket,
you can go and watch that video,
that live broadcast course.
Finally, I choose to change the fabric of the pants
into the denim fabric in our pants.
There are three types of denim fabric here.
Raw is a relatively hard denim fabric.
In the end, I want to make a relatively hard material.
So I have to choose the denim raw fabric.
Stretch has a little stretch performance.
Lightweight is relatively light.
The fold of the lightweight is more obvious.
You can use,
it should be called lightweight.
It is the denim fabric left at the end.
The second corresponding dress seems to be stretched.
Right.
Because I wanted it to have an X-shaped fold here before.
So I chose to give it here.
Let it have a stretched look.
Of course, if you don't want the whole front door to be affected,
if it is not affected,
then you have to use a fabric that is not easy to stretch.
For example,
you can use the fabric of Fusible Rigid alone.
It is a part-shaped solidification,
not a part-shaped frozen.
The part-shaped solidification and the part-shaped frozen are different.
Okay.
The next step is to make a belt.
Here,
I don't know if you usually wear a belt.
Do you find it more troublesome?
Teach you a lazy way to make a belt.
You first draw a part of the inner line.
Then,
you can use the feature to extract the part of the inner line.
Or you can draw a rectangle.
First,
make the length and height of it.
After that,
check the width of the belt.
Is it right?
For the number of the skirt,
you add this.
After adding attention,
you will receive a message from the backstage.
Okay.
Then,
we sew the rectangle and the waist together.
After the two inner lines are sewn together,
choose these two panels,
and add them to the outside.
After adding them to the outside,
the belt is worn by itself.
Isn't it amazing?
You don't have to,
oh,
put this belt on this rope.
Just,
steal a basket.
After that,
you can delete this inner line.
So that the belt can be worn by itself.
After that,
we sew the other parts on.
Sew on this belt.
You don't have to wear a belt manually.
Otherwise,
you have to open the arrangement point,
and then arrange the belt.
It's more troublesome.
Right?
You can give the thickness later.
You just add the length and thickness directly.
Then, sew it in the front here.
First, sew it into a circle.
Then, we start from this end,
sew the position where the belt will open,
and sew it here.
Add a small section to sew it up.
This is how to make a belt.
Okay.
Sometimes,
after you finish making the belt,
you will find that,
this is called a pan.
We call it a pan.
This thing,
it will,
the belt will come out.
Then, you just give it a layer.
After giving the layer,
manually drag the belt,
and then pull it back.
That's it.
Of course,
remember to return to zero after using the layer.
It doesn't mean you have to.
That is to say,
sometimes,
if you,
forget it when you simulate,
then,
it may have some conflicts with other versions.
Like here,
you will find that,
oh,
if I return it to zero,
will it be unstable?
But in fact,
we can see that,
after you untangle this version,
and then simulate it together,
it is already stable.
So,
you don't need to apply layers to it anymore.
Layer is a temporary one.
Once you simulate it to be stable,
it can always,
basically,
it can always be stable.
So, you just return the layer to zero.
Just temporarily use it.
Do you understand?
It is not a,
uh,
need to maintain the layer for a long time to be stable.
On the contrary,
if there is a dress,
you must set the layer,
otherwise,
it will not be stable.
Then,
you have to think about it.
Is this dress too tight?
Is the outer layer too tight?
Will there be this problem?
Everyone,
thank you for watching.
See you next time.
Bye.